CURRICULUM VITÆ RYAN STORM

CAREER PROFILE

Ryan is a committed developer focused on product quality. He holds a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from Concordia University with the Information Systems option from the John Molson School of Business and has over 3 years of experience in the field of web platform development.

His technical experience has been as a developer, both front and back-ends. He possesses considerable know-how in the most widespread technologies, from NodeJS, JavaScript and database systems both architecturally and functionally. He strives to master JavaScript client frameworks such as Angular with a fine ability to produce ergonomic web interfaces under HTML5 and CSS 3, while remaining flexible in his ability to quickly adapt to new technologies and systems in place. With strengths in development of automated test suites and integration, he knows how to research and carry out a complete coverage of code ensuring durability to products.

His interest in implementing industry best practices is directly reflected in the success of the projects he has worked on. He has an excellent mind for synthesis coupled with strong leadership skills. He is therefore a considerable asset in the start-up of new projects and all the more easy to integrate into teams and projects already in place.

RYAN STORM

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Specialized: Needs analysis, web application development,

micro-service architecture, user interfaces, QA, iterative/agile development, communication with

legacy systems

Other: Relational and non-relational data modeling,

ecommerce platforms, software re-engineering

COMPETENCIES

Programming languages: HTML5, JavaScript ES7, Typescript, C#,

Typescript, NodeJS, CSS 3, LESS, Sass, JQuery,

Shell

Test suites: Mocha, Chai, Karma, Jasmine, SinonJS

Development tools: Swagger, Docker, Jenkins, NGINX, Git, Atlassian

Jira, VSCode, Sourcetree, Git Bash, Visual Studio

Databases: MongoDB, SQLite, Redis, MS SQL

Operating Systems: Windows, Mac OSX, Linux, UNIX

Standards: REST, SOAP

Frameworks: Ionic, Pug, Material Design, Aurelia, Express,

AngularJS/2-7, .NET

EDUCATION

2015 B.CompSci. option Information Gina Cody School of Engineering and Computer

Science and John Molson School of Business

Concordia University

2001 DEC Industrial Design The Art Institute of Pittsburgh

AWARDS AND CERTIFICIATES

2001 Graduated Dean's List The Art Institute of Pittsburgh

LANGUAGES

French (intermediate) and English (native language)

Systems

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CGI INC.

Yellow Pages

Back-end developer September 2018 to December 2019

As part of the Zip server and PDT projects - and as a NodeJs and Angular developer respectively, Ryan was responsible for maintaining and improving the microservice architecture on the back of a data integration system to enable the migration of client accounts from a legacy system. He was also assigned to an internal Angular 4 R&D project.

He has assumed the following functions:

- · back-end data integration
- integration with third-party systems (Salesforce, Zuora, YP-Cloud)
- develop and document RESTful interfaces in front of legacy systems
- further develop existing front-end components in Typescript under Angular 4
- · complete coverage of back-end and front-end code
- · autonomous task creation and execution using Jira
- · performing various data patches
- SQL queries to aggregate the data that needs to be repaired
- write shell scripts to automatically manage server logs
- create an npm client module to unlink a dependency to further decouple a core service from smaller cloud services

Environment: JavaScript, Typescript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Angular 4, HTML 5, CSS, Sass, MongoDB, MS SQL, Elasticsearch, REST, SOAP, Jira

RXP Retail 360

Front-end developer July 2016 to October 2017

As part of the RXP Retail 360 project - Ryan completed the following activities:

- Optimized existing code by deleting repeated code into centralized functions
- developed front-end components in Typescript under Angular 4
- bug fixing

Environment: PrimeNG (Angular 4), Typescript, HTML5, CSS, Less, REST

Ville de Montréal

MEAN stack developer September 2016 to July 2017

As part of the Montréal Travail project - the client wanted to set up an independent center to monitor traffic delays related to road works throughout the city of Montreal. Ryan did the following activities:

- analyze needs, systems in place and timelines
- follow an architecture plan, data schemas and APIs (Swagger)

RYAN STORM

- develop the front and back ends, environments and databases of the platform under NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Angular 4, Bootstrap with connections to Kronos and LDAP authentication with JWT
- code coverage with unit and integration tests under Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, Karma
- · continuous integration under Docker with Jenkins and Rancher
- · perform bi-weekly demonstrations to clients
- implementation of a mobile notification service using the lonic framework
- added UI functionality for Android and iOS

Environment: NodeJS, Angular 4 (Ionic Framework), Typescript, HTML5, CSS, Less, REST, MongoDB, LDAP, Bootstrap, Swagger

Quest

MEAN stack developer March 2016 to August 2016

As an angular developer on a tele-medical web application (Spectacor), Ryan implemented various services within a controller to add features to the front of an app displaying a heart monitor.

Environment: NodeJS, AngularJS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Less, REST, MongoDB, Bootstrap

CGI Teams Mobile Web App

iOS Developer February 2016 to March 2016

As part of a developer training program on an internal iOS mobile app, he created storyboards with Xcode and Swift language.

Environment: Xcode, Swift

OMNISCIENT TECHNOLOGIES

Full-stack developer October 2017 to August 2018

As a full stack developer, on a large CMS project, during this term his responsibilities were as follows:

- created transactions between the C# API and the Angular 6 user interface
- also played as a full stack developer on a hybrid mobile application using Nodejs and the Aurelia UI framework
- helped build the CMS application based on strict specifications given by the client
- helped build the CMS using strict specifications that had to adapt to users with visual and cognitive impairments to continue browsing the application. This included the use of clientspecified screen readers, font sizes, and navigation items and colors to make the user's navigation easier

Environment: .NET Core, Angular 6, Aurelia, REST, HTML5, CSS 3